Guide to the Dwight L. Moody Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Dwight L. Moody Papers
1854-1968
RG 28
Yale University Divinity School Library
6
(17 boxes)
The collection provides valuable biographical information about Dwight Lyman Moody. Correspondence includes family letters, letters of condolence on the occasions of Moody's illness and death in 1899 and the death of his wife in 1903, letters regarding anecdotes of Moody's life, and memoirs, memos and letters compiled by his granddaughter. Sermons contain notes, transcripts and published compilations of sermons. Journals, clippings and articles consist of material describing Moody and his career. Dwight Lyman Moody was born in Northfield, Massachusetts in 1837. After organizing his own mission Sunday School in 1859, he devoted his life to evangelism, leading campaigns across the United States and Great Britain. He established two schools in Northfield: Northfield Seminary for young women and Northfield Mount Hermon School for older boys. In 1887, he founded the Chigcago Evangelization Society, which operated the Bible Training School later known as the Moody Bible Institute. Moody died on December 22, 1899 in Northfield Massachusetts.
Moody, Dwight Lyman, 1837-1899
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material compiled by Mrs. Emma Moody Powell and the Moody sermon outlines were donated by Mrs. Powell in 1962. The balance of the papers were donated in 1975 by Virginia Moody Powell McDonald, Edward M. Powell, Jr., John Douglas Powell and David Stephen Powell.
Biographical / Historical
1837 February 5 Born in Northfield, Massachusetts
1854 Left home to work for uncle in Boston
1856 Moved to Chicago
1859 Organized his own mission Sunday School
1860 Renounced his success in business, devoted himself to the evangelizing of Chicago
1861 Married Emma C. Revell, who became the mother of his three children: Emma Reynolds, William Revell and Paul Dwight.
1871 Great Chicago fire influenced Moody's decision to expand his work beyond the city of Chicago
1872 Visit to Great Britain
1873 Returned to Great Britain with Ira D. Sankey to conduct evangelistic campaigns
1875 Returned to United States as a well-known evangelist
1875-1899 Using Northfield as a home base, travelled throughout United States leading evangelistic campaigns
1879 Began his efforts to establish two schools in Northfield: Northfield Seminary for young women and Mt. Hermon for older boys
1886-1888 Annual summer conferences at the Northfield schools included special sessions for college students from which the Student Volunteer Movement arose
1887 Chicago Evangelization Society founded which operated the Bible training school later known as Moody Bible Institute
1899 December 22 Moody died in Northfield, Massachusetts
Scope and Contents
I. Correspondence, 1825-1965
II. Sermons, 1875-1899
III. Journals, Clippings, Articles about Moody, 1875-1943
The first series, Correspondence, can be divided into four categories:
a.) Letters to and from Dwight L. Moody, his wife, daughter, sons, granddaughter, secretary and other family members.
b.) Letters of condolence written on the occasions of Moody's illness and death in 1899 and the death of his wife in 1903.
c.) Letters written in response to requests for previously unpublished anecdotes of Moody's life.
d.) A group of material compiled by Moody's granddaughter, Emma Moody Fitt Powell (Mrs. Edward M. Powell), which describes chronologically the major events of Moody's life using memoirs, memos and typed copies of correspondence to and from Moody and other family members.
A considerable portion of the correspondence in Series I is that of Moody's family and his secretary, Arthur Percy Fitt. The letters of his wife, Emma C. Moody (1843-1903), are a valuable source of information about Moody's home life and travels, particularly those written to her daughter and to Mrs. Jane MacKinnon, a friend in Scotland. A. Percy Fitt who eventually married Moody's daughter, was his secretary for many years and took charge of his business affairs. After Moody's death, Fitt continued to take a leadership role in the projects which Moody had begun and also collected biographical information about Moody. His correspondence includes letters to and from evangelists Billy Sunday and Gypsy Smith as well as former associates Moody such as C.I. Scofield and G. Campbell Morgan. Some of the correspondence of family members and associates included in this series is from a time considerably after Moody's death and is not directly related to his life and activities.
The letters in Series I illustrate the wide range of associations and activities which Moody pursued throughout his life. His letters to his children and grandchildren provide a vivid insight into his personal life and family relationships. His sense of humor is particularly evident in a letter to A. Percy Fitt which he finished for his daughter, having distracted her attention from it. The correspondence also includes letters from such influential men as J. E. Kynaston Studd, Lord Cairns and the Duke of Sutherland in England and Cyrus McCormick and John Wanamaker in the United States, though the letters of these men included in this collection are not substantive in content. The collection would be most useful for biographical research about Moody, rather than research into social issues of the time.
The second series, Sermons, contains valuable original material in the form of sermon notes, as well as typed transcripts of several sermons and compilations of sermons published by the Moody Centenary Committee. Moody prepared for his many speaking engagements by labeling 5" by 8" envelopes with various subject headings and filling the envelopes with applicable material and thoughts which came to him while he studied. The contents of fifty-two such envelopes are included in this collection. Also included are fifty envelopes which were labeled with subject headings but contained no notes. Additional information about Moody's sermons is located in Series I in the material compiled by Emma Moody Powell, and in the newspaper clippings describing his evangelistic campaigns located in Series III.
The last series, Journals, Clippings, Articles, contains material describing Moody and his career. Journals by Emma C. Moody and Mrs. Jane MacKinnon shed light on Moody's 1873-1875 Great Britain campaign as well as providing information about family activities. Newspaper clipping collections are nearly complete for two campaigns, New York in 1876 and New Haven in 1878, and other clippings contained in two large scrapbooks provide a wealth of similar material. Many of the articles written in praise of Moody appeared either following his death or on the occasion of centenary celebrations in 1937.
The material compiled by Mrs. Emma Moody Powell and the Moody sermon outlines were given to the Yale Divinity School Library in 1962 by Mrs. Powell, granddaughter of Dwight L. Moody. The balance of the Moody Papers were donated to the Library in 1975 by Mrs. Powell's children: Virginia Moody Powell McDonald, Edward M. Powell Jr., John Douglas Powell and David Stephen Powell. Other Moody papers are located in the following places:
a.) Moody Museum, Northfield, Massachusetts
b.) Northfield and Mt. Hermon Schools
c.) Moody Bible Institute, Chicago, Illinois
d.) National Archives, Washington, D.C.
e.) State Historical Society of Wisconsin, Madison, Wisconsin
f.) Syracuse University Library, Syracuse, New York
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1825-1965
II. Sermons, 1875-1899
III. Journals, Clippings, Articles about Moody, 1875-1943
Evangelistic sermons; Sermons, American; United States -- Religion; Evangelists -- Great Britain; Evangelists -- United States; Fitt, Arthur Percy; Moody, Dwight Lyman, 1837-1899; Sankey, Ira David, 1840-1908; Smith, Gipsy, 1860-1947; Speer, Robert E. (Robert Elliott), 1867-1947; Studd, Kynaston, 1858-1944; Sunday, Billy, 1862-1935; Chicago Evangelization Society; Moody Bible Institute; Northfield Mount Hermon School; Northfield School
- Correspondence, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE is divided as follows:
  a.) Correspondence of Dwight L. Moody
  b.) Correspondence of Emma C. Moody (wife)
  c.) Correspondence of A. Percy Fitt (secretary and son-in-law)
  d.) Correspondence of Emma R. Moody (Mrs. A.P. Fitt and daughter)
  e.) Correspondence of William R. Moody (son)
  f.) Correspondence of Emma Moody Fitt (Mrs. E.M. Powell, granddaughter)
  g.) Correspondence of other family members and associates.
  The letters in each section are arranged alphabetically. Any "Illegible signatures" or "Miscellaneous fragments" are located at the end of each section.
  Letters of Condolence are found in five scrapbooks. Letters of condolence from more notable persons are mentioned in the index of the material compiled by Emma Moody Powell.
  Letters of Anecdotes for Biographers were written primarily to A.P. Fitt or W.R. Moody in response to personal requests or in response to an advertisement, an example of which is attached to the letter of M.D. Wood in this section. The letters are arranged alphabetically by author.
  Material Compiled by Emma Moody Powell has been left in the chronological order in which it was received. The first folder in this section contains a table of contents and foreword written by Mrs. Powell as well as copies of the descriptive lists of letters, memos and memoirs for each year, consolidated to facilitate research. Some of the originals of this correspondence are located within the collection.
  - Correspondence of Dwight L. Moody
    - [Anderson?], Annie, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - S. Bagster Sons ltd., 1895 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Barker [?], 1893 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Booth, Ballington, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bryan, William Jennings, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cairns, 1st Earl, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Cairns, M.H., 1875 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - [Coyle?],Thomas, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Currier, R.B., 1880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cutler, Henry F., 1895, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dodge, William E. Jr., 1875, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Erdman, [Charles R?], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fitt, Arthur Percy, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Fitt, Arthur Percy, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fitt, Emma Moody (Mrs. E.M. Powell), 1896-1899 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Fitt, Frank, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Gaylord, A.F., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Greene, A., 1872 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hall, Evelyn, 1893, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hall [T. Farmer?], 1882 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Harper, William R, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Holton, Samuel, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hulbert, Gertrude, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Ignatius of Jesus, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Keebaugh, J.D., 1877 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Kershaw, Caroline, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Matlack, Thomas, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - McCormick, Cyrus H., 1887 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - McCormick, Nettie F., 1895 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - MacKinnon, Jane, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Moody, Betsey Holton, 1857-1893 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Moody Elizabeth, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Moody, Emma Reynolds, 1887-1890 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Moody, Emma Reynolds, 1893-1899 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Moody, George, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Moody, Luther, 1857, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Moody, William R, 1890-1898 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Moore, H.M., 1897 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Mott, John R., 1889-1899 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Thos. Nelson Sons, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Norton, William, 1898, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ober, C.K., 1886 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Phillips [Phillip], 1888, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Rankin, Henry W., 1884-1893 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Rhead, Louis, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - [Seelye, Henry E.?], 1881 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Smith, L.H., 1896 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Studd, J.E. Kynaston, 1882, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Sutherland, 3rd Duke of (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Talmadge, T. Dewitt, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Varley [Sarah?], 1896 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Whittle, D.W., 1889 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Wilson, James A., 1897 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Fragments, Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence of Emma C. Moody
    - Aberdeen, Tohbel, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Billings, Julia, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Cairns, M.H., 1884, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Ewing, Edith, [1900?] (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Fitt, Emma Moody, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Gould, Helen Miller, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Kelman, John, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Kinnaird, Alma, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - McKenzie, Alexander, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - McKinley, William, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - MacKinnon, Jane (Jessie?), 1874-1884 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - MacKinnon, Jane, 1885-1900 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Mikamb'e, S.M., 1900 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Moody, Ambert, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Moody, Betsey Holton, 1861-1889 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Moody, Emma Reynolds, 1892-1902 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Moody, Samuel, 1866 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - [Parry?], Gertrude, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Rankin, Henry, 1884-1901 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Reese, Anna Revell, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Revell, Mrs. Fleming, 1873-1892 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Stebbins, [Mrs. George C?], 1897 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Varley, [Sarah?], 1898-1899 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Fragments (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence of A. Percy Fitt
    - Booth, William, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Cleworth, Thos. E., 1882 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Coolidge, Calvin, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Grenfell, Wilfred T., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Keisen, Mori, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - King, Simeon, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Meyer, F.B., 1899-1928 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Morgan, G. Campbell, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Sankey, Ira D., 1896 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Scofield, C.I., 1909 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Smith, Gypsy, 1906-1937 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Speer, Robert, 1906-1910 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Stebbins, George, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Studd, Charles T., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Sunday, William A. (Mrs. A.P. Fitt), 1908, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence of Emma R. Moody
    - Hall, Maria R., 1903 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Kinnaird, [Emily?], 1903 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Moody, Ambert, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Rankin, Henry, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Sangster, Margaret, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Silverthorne, Mary E., 1877 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Simpson, M.S., 1903 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Speer, Robert F., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Stebbins, George C., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Varley, Sarah, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence of William R. Moody
    - Bennett, George, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Gould, Helen Miller, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Kinnaird, Lord Arthur, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Lawrence, William, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Moffat, James, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Mott, John R., 1932 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Smith, George Adam (Mrs. E.M. Powell), 1899,1900 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence of Emma Moody Fitt
    - Abell, Bess (sec'y. Mrs. L.B. Johnson), 1965, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Chichester, Gerald (sec'y. Queen Mary), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Degenfeld, Henry Count (for Empress), 1940 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Fitt, A. Percy, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Humphrey, Hubert, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Mott, John R., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1939-1949 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Sankey, Ira D., 1895 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Stagg, Amos Alonzo, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Studd, J.E.K., 1937 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence of Other Family Members and Associates
    - Hulbert, Gertrude, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Moody, Luther, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Moody, May Whittle, 1937,1941 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Moody, Paul D., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Sankey, Ira D., 1874 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Letters of Condolence
    - Scrapbook of English Letters death of D.L. Moody, 1899 (Box 3)
    - Scrapbook of American Letters death of D.L. Moody, 1899 (Box 4)
    - Scrapbook of letters received by D.L. Moody during his last illness, 1899 (Box 5)
    - Scrapbook of letters to Emma and Percy Fitt after death of D.L. Moody, 1899 (Box 5)
    - Scrapbook of cablegrams and telegrams received after death of D.L.Moody, 1899 (Box 6)
    - Scrapbook of letters received after death of Mrs. D.L. Moody, 1903 (Box 6)
  - Letters of Anecdotes for Biographers
    - A - B, 1923,1968 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - C, 1900-1953 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - D - F, 1908-1939 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - G - Hi, 1900-1943 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Ho - Hu, 1900-1944 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - J - McCormick, 1905-1937 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - McCoy-Montgomery, 1907-1937 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Moody-Mowle, 1900-1937 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - N - P, 1900-1930 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - O- R, 1909-1940 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - S, 1907-1968 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - T--V, 1909-1923 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - W-Wilson, Charles l900, 1910,n.d. (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Wilson, Woodid-Wo Anonymous, 1914-1938 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Material Compiled by Emma Moody Powell
    - Index, Foreword, Descriptive Lists of Contents (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Contents, 1854, 1855 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Contents, 1856, 1857 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Contents, 1858, 1859 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Contents, 1860, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Contents, 1862, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Contents, 1864, 1865 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Contents, 1866, 1867 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Contents, 1868, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Contents, 1870, 1871 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Contents, 1872, 1873 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Contents, 1874, 1875 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Contents, 1876, 1877 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Contents, 1878, 1879 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Contents, 1880, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Contents, 1882, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Contents, 1884, 1885 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Contents, 1886, 1887 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Contents, 1888, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Contents, 1890, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Contents, 1892, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Contents, 1894, 1895 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Contents, 1896, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Contents, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - Contents, 1899 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Condolences A-M, 1899-1900 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - Condolences O-W, 1899-1900 (Box 9, Folder 111)
    - Excerpts from Founder's Day Address Sermon outlines listed by place, date and collection A-G (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - Sermon outline dates H-W (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - Way to God Anecdotes (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Sermon Anecdotes (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Letter to Paul D. Moody, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 114)
- Sermons, Series II
  This series is divided into the following categories:
  a) Sermon Notes are arranged alphabetically by subject. Moody often marked a series of dates and places at which a particular sermon was delivered. When dates were available, only the earliest date has been indicated. The marked envelope fronts or separate dating sheets retained in each subject folder provide more complete information.
  b) Empty Sermon Note Envelopes are arranged alphabetically.
  c) Typed Sermon Transcripts are arranged alphabetically by title. In many cases these transcripts were taken from newspaper accounts of Moody's campaigns.
  d) Centenary Committee Publications--Ten sermons and a booklet of illustrations used by Moody were published by the Moody Centenary Committee for the celebration of 1937.
  - Sermon notes
    - Absalom, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Barnabas, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Behold, 1876 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Bible Marking, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Bring Him Unto Me, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Character, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Compassion, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Conscience (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Cornelius, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Deliverance, 1876 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Emblems of the Holy Spirit--Fire, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Excuses, 1897 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Faith, 1875 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Faith, Courage, Enthusiasm, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Fear Not, 1881 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - First Charge Not Ashamed (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Fool, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Four Men Called to Higher Service, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Gift of God is Eternal Life, 1877 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Grace No. 2, 1878 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Haggai, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Jehosaphat, 1880 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Job, 1888 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - John, 1882 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - John 20, 1882 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Jonathan, 1894 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Joseph, 1888 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Joshua, 1876 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Keep Thy Heart, 1888 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Lectures on the Bible (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Life More Abundant (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Little Things, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Luke, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Luke 7, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Matthew (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Naaman, 1876 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Nameless Charities (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Nehemiah, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Numbers 6: 24-27, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Obedience, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Peter, 1876 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Psalm 23, 1896 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Psalms 51 and 32 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Recovering of Sight to the Blind, 1876 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Repent and Believe the Gospel (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Repentence, 1875 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Romans 8, 1885 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Saul, 1896 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - "Scraps'', n.d. (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Second Coming (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Six Steps in Downfall of Jesus (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Sons of God, 1895 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Suffering, 1895 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Thief, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Titus, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Transfiguration, 1894 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Twelve Spies and Caleb (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Unbelief, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Warning, 1879 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - What God is Able to Do, 1899 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - What Produces Convictions? (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - What Think Ye of Christ (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - The Wicked Do Not Live Out Half Their Days", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Will of God, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Empty Sermon Note Envelopes
    - A-B (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - C (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - D-F (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - G-I (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - J-M (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - N-P (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - R-W (Box 12, Folder 61)
  - Typed Sermon Transcripts
    - Annointing of the Spirit, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 62)
    - Different Types of Christians, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 62)
    - The Gift of Power, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 62)
    - God is Love, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 63)
    - God is Love, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 63)
    - The Holy Spirit, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - Holy Spirit, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - Holy Spirit, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - Holy Spirit, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - The Holy Spirit, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - Holy Spirit, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - Holy Spirit, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - Holy Spirit, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - Holy Spirit, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - Holy Spirit, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - The Holy Spirit-Illustrations, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - Rest for the Weary, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 66)
    - Story of Nicodemus, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Centenary Committee Publications